Guide to the Francis Griffith Newlands Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Norton, Charles Dyer 1871-1922
O'Brien Robert Lincoln 1865-1955
Ogden, J. C.
Oliver, Robert Shaw 1847-1935
Osborn, William H.
Osborne, Thomas Mott 1859-1926
Oulahan, Richard Victor 1867-1931
Owens, Clarence Julian 1877-
Oxnard, Henry Thomas 1860-1922
Pack, Charles Lathrop 1857-1937
Page, Thomas Walker 1866-1937
Parker, Walter
Parry, David Maclean 1852-1915
Parry, Will H. 1864-1917
Parsons, William Barclay 1859-1932
Patrick, Lloyd B.
Patten, James Horace 1877-1940
Pence, Thomas Jones 1873-1916
Penn, Alfred
Perkins, Edmund Taylor 1861-1921
Perkins, George Walbridge 1824-1920
Peters, Andrew James 1872-1938
Phelan, James Duval 1861-1930
Philbrick, Wilma H.
Phillips, William 1878-
Potter, Albert Franklin 1859-
Powell, George Harold 1872-1922
Prendergast, William A. 1867-1954
Preston, James Harry 1860-1938
Preston, Robert E.
Price, Overton Westfeldt 1873-1914
Pritchett, Henry Smith 1857-l939
Prouty, Charles Azro 1853-1921
Pryor, Ike T. 1852-1937
Pugh, Arthur Benton 1854-1916
Purdy, Milton Dwight 1866-1937
Pyne, George D.
Quick, (John) Herbert 1861-1925
Rankin, John Hall 1868-1952
Reber, Frank L.
Requa, Mark Laurence 1866-1937
Rhoades, John Harsen 1869-1943
Riddle, William
Ridgely, William Barret 1858-1920
Ridsdale, Percival Sheldon 1872-1953
Riesenberg, Henry
Riker, Carroll Livingston 1854-1931
Riley, Franklin Lafayette 1868-1929
Ripley, William Zebina 1867-1941
Roberts, George Evan 1857-1948
Robinson, Charles Mulford 1869-1917
Roeper, James
Rogers, Sam L.
Rolph, James, Jr. 1869-1934
Roper, Daniel Calhoun 1867-1943
Ross, Gilbert C.
Rudolph, Guno Hugo 1860-1932
Russell, George 1837-1924
Saltzgaber, Gaylord Miller 1846-
Sanford John B. 1869-
Schoepf, W(illiam) Kesley 1864-1927
Schurz, Carl Lincoln 1871-1924
Schwam, Theodore 1841-1926
Scofield, Carl Schurz 1875-
Scott, Charles 1847-1916
Scott, James Brown 1866-1943
Seligman, Isaac Newton 1856-1917
Sellers, Horace Wells 1857-1933
Sells, Cato
Sewall, Frank 1837-1915
Shair, F. J.
Shallenberger, William Shadrach 1839-1914
Sharon, William E.
Shaughnessy, J. F.
Shaw, Albert 1857-1947
Shibley, George H.
Shipp, Thomas Roerty 1875-1952
Short, Frank H(armilton) 1862-1920
Sioussat, St. George Leakin 1878-
Skaggs, R. E.
Slattery, Harry A. 1887-1949
Slevater, David
Smalley, P. J.
Smith, Hugh McCormick 1865-1941
Smith, James Francis 1859-1928
Smith, Joseph Russell 1874-
Smith, Philip Sidney 1877-1949
Smith, William Wolff
Smythe, William Ellsworth 1861-1922
Spear, Ellis 1834-1917
Spelling, Thomas Carl
Sprague, Frank Julian 1857-1934
Sprague, Homer Baxter 1829-1918
Start, Edwin Augustus 1863-1923
Stein, Robert 1857-1917
Sternberg, George Miller 1838-1915
Stevenson, William Holmes 1857-1930
Stewart, Joseph 1859-1929
Stillwell, Lewis Buckley 1863-1941
Stockton, Charles Herbert 1845-1923
Stokes, J. G. Phelps
Stone, Charles Augustus 1867-1941
Stone, G. F.
Stone, Warren Sanford 1860-1925
Stratton, Samuel Wesley 1861-1931
Stubbe, Joseph Edward 1850-1914
Sweeney, James G. 1877-
Taggart, Thomas 1856-1929
Tallman, Clay
Taylor, Edward Robeson 1838-1923
Taylor, Robert Stewart 1838-1918
Taylor, William Alton 1863-1949
Teele, Ray Palmer 1868-1927
Thatcher, George B.
Thatcher, L. R.
Thompson, John Taliaferro 1860-1940
Thorp, Freeman
Todd, George Carroll 1879-1947
Tomkins, Calvin 1858-1921
Trowbridge, S (amuel) Breck Barkman 1862-1925
Tumulty, Joseph Patrick 1879-1954
Turley, Jay 1877-1942
Tweed, Char1es Harrison 1844-1917
Twitchell, Ralph Emerson 1859-1925
Underwood, E. Marvin
Valentine, Robert Groavenor 1872-1916
vanderlip, Frank Arthur 1864-1937
Van Nagell, J. R.
Van Norman, Louis Edwin 1869-1956
Vrooman, Carl
Walcutt, Charles C. Jr. 1861-
Walker, Francis 187O-1950
Walker, H.
Walker, John Grimes 1835-1907
Wallace, Albert J.
Wallace, William, Jr. 1864-1939
Waller, Gilbert Johnson 1859-
Walworth, Ellen Hardin 1832-1915
Watkins, Edgar 1868-1945
Waymire, James A.
Wells, Philip Patterson 1868-
Wescott, John Wesley 1849-1927
West, Charles 1872-
West, Oswald
Wheeler, William Riley 1860-1935
Wiley, Harvey Washington 1844-1930
Will, Thomas Elmer 1861-
Willey, Henry Ide
Williams, George Fred 1852-1932
Williams, John Skelton 1865-1926
Willsie, Honoré
Wilson, Huntington 1875
Wilson, James Grant 1832-1914
Wilson Jesse Everett 1867-1945
Wingfield, George 1876-
Winslow, Erving 1839-1922
Winterhalter, Albert Gustavus 1856-1920
Woodburn, Wlliam, Jr.
Woodruff, Francis Eben 1844-1914
Woods, Albert Fred 1866-1948
Woodson, Urey 1859-1939
Wyman, Charles M.
*Wythe, Frederick S.
Yard, Robert Sterling 1861-1945
Young, Richard Whitehead 1858-1919
Zalinski, Edmund Louis Gray 1849-1909
Bimetallism; Conservation of natural resources; Drainage -- United States; Environmental protection; Flood control -- Law and legislation -- United States; Forests and forestry; Interstate commerce; Irrigation -- United States; Railroads and state -- United States; Reclamation of land -- Law and legislation -- United States; Silver question; Transportation -- Law and legislation -- United States; Water -- Law and legislation -- United States; Waterways -- United States; Nevada -- Politics and government; United States -- Politics and government; Washington (D.C.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; West (U.S.); Maps; Scrapbooks; Lawyers; Legislators; Politicians; Public officials; Bartine, Horace F. (Horace Franklin), 1848-1918; Bartlett, George A. (George Arthur), 1869-1951; Bingham, Ernest L.; Boyd, James T.; Callbreath, James Finch, 1858-1940; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Davies, Joseph Edward, 1876-1958; Dennett, Fred, 1863-1928; Dennis, John Hancock, 1835-; Finch, James D.; Friend, Harvey M.; Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934; Herrin, William F. (William Franklin), 1854-1927; Hooker, Arthur; Hudson, Millard Filmore; Lane, Franklin K.; Martin, Anne, 1875-1951; Maxwell, George Hebard, 1860-1946; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; Newell, Frederick Haynes, 1862-1932; Newlands, Francis G. (Francis Griffith), 1848-1917; Nixon, George Stuart, 1860-1912; Perkins, Edmund Taylor, 1864-1921; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Pittman, Key, 1872-1940; Ramsdell, Joseph Eugene, 1858-1954; Reber, Frank; Roff, Nathan W.; Sharon, William E.; Shipp, Thomas Roerty, 1875-1952; Smith, George Otis, 1871-1944; Smith, Herbert Knox, 1869-1931; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Van Duzer, Clarence D. (Clarence Dunn), 1866-1947; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; United States. Congress. Senate; United States. Interstate Trade Commission; United States. National Waterways Commission; Democratic Party (Nev.); National Reclamation Association; Silver Party (Nev.); International Irrigation Congress; National Rivers and Harbors Congress
- Correspondence and papers, 1869-1917; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, consists of fifty-six boxes of Newlands's incoming and outgoing letters. The correspondence is arranged in chronological order. An alphabetical list of correspondents is appended at the end of this register, and correspondence to or from individuals named on this list may be located by consulting the Manuscripts and Archives Departmental catalog.
  Though the earlist items in the series date from 1869 the bulk of the correspondence dates after Newlands's election the Senate in 1902. Correspondents include constituents, other Nevada politicians, elected representatives from other states, members of the Democratic Party hierarchy, and leaders of several national organizations concerned with issues such as the improvement of inland waterways, flood control, irrigation and transportation. Newlands's interest in the preservation of the beauty of Washington, D.C. is discussed in correspondence with several prominent architects. The volume of correspondence increases steadily and in proportion to Newlands's seniority and prominence in national politics. The most voluminous correspondence dates from 1913 and 1914 following the election of Democratic President Woodrow Wilson.
  The earliest correspondence contains occasional references to Newlands's legal career in San Francisco, his concerns over investments as trustee of his father-in-law's estate, and his interests in the development of the Washington, D.C. suburb of Chevy Chase, Maryland. Correspondence from Newlands's career in the U.S. House of Representatives is sparse and mainly concerns the interests of constituents in military appointments, pensions, or post office matters.
  Beginning in 1902 the correspondence contains more substantive exchanges on Nevada fusion party politics and the alignment of Nevada Democrats with Silver Party interests. Major correspondents at this time include William E. Sharon, and Nathan W.Roff, chairman and secretary, respectively, of the Silver Party State Central Committee; John H. Dennis of the Reno Journal; Clarence Van Duzen, Newlands's private secretary who became Congressman from Nevada when Newlands was elected to the Senate; Ernest L. Bingham, editor of the Nevada State Journal; H. F. Bartine; and John Sparks, the governor of Nevada. Later Nevada political matters are discussed in correspondence with Frank Reber, managing editor of the Reno Gold Circle News; James T. Boyd, a Nevada state senator; and George A. Bartlett, who succeeded Van Duzen as representative at large in 1908. Some of Newlands's interest in irrigation is reflected in correspondence with William Franklin Herrin, general attorney of the Southern Pacific Company, but there is surprisingly little documentation on the important 1902 Newlands's Reclamation Act.
  Newlands's continuing interests in the problems of inland waterways led to his appointment to the Inland Waterways Commission in 1907. There is correspondence with Gifford Pinchot on this work. There are also exchanges with Millard F. Hudson, Newlands's clerk or secretary, during Newlands's cruise down the Mississippi with the commission. As is generally the case during Newlands's periodic absences from Washington the correspondence with office staff members is detailed and reveals Newlands's thoughts and concerns. Letters from staff members picture the workings of the office.
  By 1909 the proportion of constituent correspondence decreases noticeably, and there are a greater number of exchanges with representatives of national lobbying organizations and federal bureaus and commissions. Some of these involve Newlands's position as a vice-president of the National Rivers and Harbors Congress and work with Louisiana Senator and Congress president Joseph Eugene Ransdell, while correspondence with James Finch Callbreath concerns the American Mining Congress. The most frequent exchanges concern the National Irrigation Association which became the National Reclamation Association. With its program for the "advancement of forestry, irrigation, drainage, flood prevention, and river regulation", and for "expansion of interal trade and the creation of larger home markets" the association most closely represented Newlands's own interests, and its director George H. Maxwell was an inveterate campaigner with Newlands. Other association correspondents include: Edmund T. Perkins of the National Drainage Congress and the American Reclamation Federation; Thomas R. Shipp, executive secretary of the National Conservation Congress; and Arthur Hooker, secretary of the National Irrigation Congress. Federal officials of importance to Newlands's various legislative programs include Frederick Haynes Newell, director of the U.S. Reclamation Service, Fred Dennett, commissioner of the General Land Office; George Otis Smith, director of the U.S. Geological Survey; and Herbert Knox Smith and Joseph E. Davies, both commissioners of the Bureau of Corporations. There are relatively few exchanges with Republican Presidents Theodore Roosevelt and William Howard Taft.
  The 1912 correspondence reflects Newlands's participation in the Democrative presidential campaign, and there are exchanges with Franklin K.Lane, William Gibbs McAdoo, Josephus Daniels, and Woodrow Wilson. Some of the correspondence in June 1912 concenns Newlands's attempt to introduce a Negro disfranchisement plank into the Democratic platform. Letters discussing Newlands's involvement in an investigation of the Titanic disaster are also present in 1912 files. Nevada politics is again a concern following the death of Senator George S. Nixon, and there is correspondence concerning Key Pittman, the Nevada Democrat elected to the Senate in 1912.
  The voluminous 1913 and 1914 correspondence files contain many letters concerning tariff issues. Constituents, such as George Wingfield, write frequently expressing views on the protection of wool, sugar beets, meats, and other Western products and on Panama Canal tolls. In April 1913 there is extremely heavy correspondence relating to Newlands's bill for the creation of a Board of River Regulation. Newlands's bill creating an Interstate Trade Commission is the subject of many exchanges in 1914. There are also several discussions of Newlands's support for women's suffrage in exchanges with Anne H. Martin, president of the Nevada Equal Franchise Society.
  There is a marked decrease in the correspondence from 1915 until Newlands's death in 1917. Some correspondence concerns the Interstate Commerce Commission, and there are also exchanges with architect Cass Gilbert and others attempting to prevent the erection of a central power plant in Washington, D.C. Correspondence with James D. Finch, Newlands's secretary at the time, concerns Nevada election campaigning for Wilson, but there is relatively little correspondence concerning the National Democratic Party, its 1916 convention, or platform. Newlands's concerns about labor and the railroads during World War I are not discussed in any substantive way in the series.
  At the end of the series there are three letterbooks containing copies of Newlands's outgoing public letters for the period 1899-1905, some signed by Newlands's clerk at the time, Harvey M. Friend.
  Arrangement
  This series contains material arranged in chronological order.
  - 1869-1899 April 1869-1899 April (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - 1899 May-1900 May 1899 May-1900 May (Box 2, Folder 14-24)
  - 1900 June-1901 December 1900 June-1901 December (Box 3, Folder 25-36)
  - 1902 January-1902 May 1902 January-1902 May (Box 4, Folder 37-43)
  - 1902 June-1903 April 1902 June-1903 April (Box 5, Folder 44-53)
  - 1903 May-1904 March 1903 May-1904 March (Box 6, Folder 54-64)
  - 1904 April-1905 January 1904 April-1905 January (Box 7, Folder 65-75)
  - 1905 February-December 1905 February-December (Box 8, Folder 76-84)
  - 1906 January-May 1906 January-May (Box 9, Folder 85-91)
  - 1906 June-1907 May 1906 June-1907 May (Box 10, Folder 92-103)
  - 1907 June-November 1907 June-November (Box 11, Folder 104-112)
  - 1907 December-1908 January 1907 December-1908 January (Box 12, Folder 113-120)
  - 1908 February-April 10 1908 February-April 10 (Box 13, Folder 121-131)
  - 1908 April 11-August 10 1908 April 11-August 10 (Box 14, Folder 132-141)
  - 1908 August 11-November 1908 August 11-November (Box 15, Folder 142-151)
  - 1908 December-1909 February 1908 December-1909 February (Box 16, Folder 152-162)
  - 1909 March-May 1909 March-May (Box 17, Folder 163-173)
  - 1909 June-September 1909 June-September (Box 18, Folder 174-183)
  - 1909 October-December 1909 October-December (Box 19, Folder 184-193)
  - 1910 January-March 10 1910 January-March 10 (Box 20, Folder 194-201)
  - 1910 March 11-May 1910 March 11-May (Box 21, Folder 202-208)
  - 1910 June-October 1910 June-October (Box 22, Folder 209-215)
  - 1910 November-1911 February 1910 November-1911 February (Box 23, Folder 216-227)
  - 1911 March-May 1911 March-May (Box 24, Folder 228-237)
  - 1911 June-October 1911 June-October (Box 25, Folder 238-249)
  - 1911 November-1912 January 1911 November-1912 January (Box 26, Folder 250-260)
  - 1912 February-March 1912 February-March (Box 27, Folder 261-272)
  - 1912 April-May 9 1912 April-May 9 (Box 28, Folder 273-283)
  - 1912 May 10-June 1912 May 10-June (Box 29, Folder 284-296)
  - 1912 July-August 5 1912 July-August 5 (Box 30, Folder 297-309)
  - 1912 August 6-October 9 1912 August 6-October 9 (Box 31, Folder 310-321)
  - 1912 October 10-December 13 1912 October 10-December 13 (Box 32, Folder 322-333)
  - 1912 December 14-1913 January 17 1912 December 14-1913 January 17 (Box 33, Folder 334-342)
  - 1913 January 18-March 7 1913 January 18-March 7 (Box 34, Folder 343-350)
  - 1913 March 8-April 14 1913 March 8-April 14 (Box 35, Folder 351-358)
  - 1913 April 15-May 8 1913 April 15-May 8 (Box 36, Folder 359-369)
  - 1913 May 9-May 29 1913 May 9-May 29 (Box 37, Folder 370-380)
  - 1913 May 30-June 24 1913 May 30-June 24 (Box 38, Folder 381-391)
  - 1913 June 25-August 20 1913 June 25-August 20 (Box 39, Folder 392-402)
  - 1913 August 21-October 16 1913 August 21-October 16 (Box 40, Folder 403-413)
  - 1913 October 17-November 30 1913 October 17-November 30 (Box 41, Folder 414-424)
  - 1913 December 1-1914 January 8 1913 December 1-1914 January 8 (Box 42, Folder 425-437)
  - 1914 January 9-February 11 1914 January 9-February 11 (Box 43, Folder 438-450)
  - 1914 February 12-March 15 1914 February 12-March 15 (Box 44, Folder 451-464)
  - 1914 March 16-April 18 1914 March 16-April 18 (Box 45, Folder 465-477)
  - 1914 April 19-May 25 1914 April 19-May 25 (Box 46, Folder 478-489)
  - 1914 May 26-July 16 1914 May 26-July 16 (Box 47, Folder 490-501)
  - 1914 July 17-September 14 1914 July 17-September 14 (Box 48, Folder 502-514)
  - 1914 September 15-November 19 1914 September 15-November 19 (Box 49, Folder 515-524)
  - 1914 November 20-1915 January 24 1914 November 20-1915 January 24 (Box 50, Folder 525-536)
  - 1915 January 25-April 30 1915 January 25-April 30 (Box 51, Folder 537-545)
  - 1915 May 1-October 30 1915 May 1-October 30 (Box 52, Folder 546-556)
  - 1915 November 1-1916 February 18 1915 November 1-1916 February 18 (Box 53, Folder 557-563)
  - 1915 February 19-1916 October 6 1915 February 19-1916 October 6 (Box 54, Folder 564-574)
  - 1916 October 7-1917 October 15 1916 October 7-1917 October 15 (Box 55, Folder 575-587)
  - 1917 October 17-Dec, undated 1917 October 17-Dec, undated (Box 56, Folder 588-589)
  - Letterbooks
    - 1899 December 6-1900 June 12 1899 December 6-1900 June 12 (Box 56, Folder 590)
    - 1900 July 17-1901 March 15 1900 July 17-1901 March 15 (Box 56, Folder 591)
    - 1904 May 6-1905 December 1 1904 May 6-1905 December 1 (Box 56, Folder 592)
- Topical files, 1869 - 1936; Series II
  SERIES II, TOPICAL FILES, includes material filed by subject which reflects Newlands's interests in various programs and pieces of legislation. Files may contain Newlands's views as expressed in speeches, Senate hearings and testimony, articles, drafts of legislation, and notes. The files also include background material such as minutes, reports, U.S. Government Printing Office publications, copies of bills, speeches and writings of others, issues of professional journals and popular periodicals, clippings, maps, charts, and photographs.
  Many of Newlands's campaign speeches are filed in the section Political Issues along with delegate lists, platforms, endorsements, posters, and other campaign memorabilia. Other campaign material is found in folders 711-712. The section Speeches is composed of a paste-up of a publication "Remarks of the Honorable Francis G. Newlands" which includes Newlands's speeches in Congress. Waterways is the largest section, but there are also substantive files under Foreign relations, Interstate Trade Commission, Irrigation, and Railroads. Files under Miscellanea relate to some of Newlands's less well documented concerns such as the Washington, D.C. central power plant issue and its zoo; the development of Chevy Chase, Maryland; and the Titanic disaster.
  This series contains files arranged alphabetically by topic. Material for each topic is arranged alphabetically by record type and/or topic. Miscellanea is arranged at the end of the series.
  - Foreign relations
    - General, undated (Box 57, Folder 593)
    - Cuba, 1898-1900 (Box 57, Folder 594)
    - Hawaii, 1898-1900 (Box 57, Folder 595-597)
    - Panama Canal, 1912-1914 (Box 57, Folder 598-600)
    - Nicaragua Canal, 1893-1900 (Box 57, Folder 601)
    - Nicaragua and Panama Canal, 1899-1913 (Box 57, Folder 602)
    - Philippines, 1899 (Box 58, Folder 603-604)
    - Puerto Rico, 1899-1900 (Box 58, Folder 605-608)
  - Forests
    - Maps, 1907-1911 (Box 59, Folder 609)
    - Petitions, 1913 (Box 59, Folder 610)
    - Printed material, 1908 (Box 59, Folder 611)
    - Reports, 1906-1908 (Box 59, Folder 612)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1907-1909 (Box 59, Folder 613)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1910-1913 (Box 59, Folder 614)
  - Interstate Trade Commission
    - General, 1911-1914 (Box 60, Folder 615-623)
    - H. R. 15613, undated (Box 60, Folder 624)
    - Printed material, 1889-1917 (Box 61, Folder 625-626)
    - S. 4160, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 627-629)
    - Senate bills, 1911-1912 (Box 61, Folder 630)
  - Irrigation
    - Article, 1906 (Box 62, Folder 631)
    - Bills, 1890-1901 (Box 62, Folder 632-634)
    - Clippings and circulars, 1904-1915 (Box 62, Folder 635)
    - Committee on Public Lands, 1901 (Box 62, Folder 636)
    - Democratic measure, undated (Box 62, Folder 637)
    - Democrats, 1900-1904 (Box 62, Folder 638)
    - Maps, 1905 (Box 62, Folder 639)
    - National Conservation Commission, 1908 (Box 62, Folder 640)
    - National Irrigation Congress, 1907-1912 (Box 62, Folder 641-643)
    - Newspapers, 1901-1910 (Box 63, Folder 644-646)
    - Owens Valley, 1904-1906 (Box 63, Folder 647-648)
    - Speeches, 1904-1905 (Box 63, Folder 649-651)
    - Miscellanea, undated (Box 63, Folder 652-655)
  - Political issues
    - General, 1899-1916, undated (Box 64, Folder 656-667)
    - General, 1899-1916, undated (Box 65, Folder 668-675)
    - Campaign finances, 1908 (Box 65, Folder 676)
    - Finances, 1910 (Box 65, Folder 677)
    - Nevada, Oregon, and California, undated (Box 65, Folder 678)
    - Posters, undated (Box 65, Folder 679)
  - Railroads
    - General, 1900-1914, undated (Box 66, Folder 680-682)
    - Article, 1905 (Box 66, Folder 683)
    - Bills, 1899-1917 (Box 66, Folder 684)
    - Employees, 1915-1916 (Box 66, Folder 685)
    - Incorporation, 1900-1910 (Box 66, Folder 686)
    - National incorporation, 1899-1916 (Box 66, Folder 687-690)
    - Printed material, 1899-1917 (Box 67, Folder 691-694)
    - Speeches: clippings, 1907-1910 (Box 67, Folder 695)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Indices, 1912-1913 (Box 67, Folder 696-698)
  - Silver
    - General, 1870-1900 (Box 68, Folder 699)
    - Printed material, 1896-1900 (Box 68, Folder 700)
    - Reports, 1896-1900 (Box 68, Folder 701)
    - Speeches, 1896-1897, undated (Box 68, Folder 702)
  - Speeches
    - U.S. Congress, 58th, 1904-1905 (Box 69, Folder 703)
    - U.S. Congress, 60th, 1908-1909 (Box 69, Folder 704)
    - U.S. Congress, 62nd, 1911-1912 (Box 69, Folder 705-709)
    - Miscellaneous, 1905-1915 (Box 69, Folder 710)
  - U.S. Senate bills, 1902-1908 (Box 70, Folder 711-712)
  - Waterways
    - General, 1912-1914 (Box 70, Folder 713-718)
    - Bills (Box 70)
      - General, 1907-1915 (Box 70, Folder 719-723)
      - General, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 724-725)
      - Conservation, 1914-1915 (Box 71, Folder 726)
      - Flood control, 1916 (Box 71, Folder 727)
      - Rivers and harbors, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 728)
    - Committee report, 1914 (Box 71, Folder 729)
    - Lake Washington Canal, 1910 (Box 71, Folder 730)
    - Press releases, 1912-1916 (Box 71, Folder 731-732)
    - Printed material, 1898-1907 (Box 71, Folder 733-734)
    - Printed material, 1908-1913 (Box 72, Folder 735-743)
    - Printed material, 1914-1917, undated (Box 73, Folder 744-747)
    - Speeches, 1907-1911 (Box 73, Folder 748-752)